Please watch the following video
これからビデオをご覧いただきます
that contains heartfelt comments
ロシアで迫害を受けている兄弟姉妹の
from persecuted brothers
心のこもったコメントを
聞くことができます
and sisters in Russia,
and see why we have no reason
to fear persecution.
私たちが迫害を恐れる必要が
全くないことも分かるでしょう
ある家で集会を開いていた時
I was horrified when several masked officers
急に 2つのドアが開き
broke down two doors and burst into the home
覆面をした警察官たちが
踏み込んできました
where the meeting was being held.
Everything happened at once
怖かったです
あっという間の出来事でした
—loud sounds, noise,
大きな音がして
the order:
“Everyone sit on the floor!”
「全員床に座れ！」と命令されました
手錠を掛けられ 車に乗せられ
I was overcome with fear when they put me
in handcuffs, placed me in the police van,
刑務所に連れていかれました
and took me to jail.
怖かったです
I was afraid
刑務所にどれぐらいいることになるか
because I didn’t know how long
何が起きるか分からなかったので
怖かったです
I would be there and what was awaiting me.
尋問中 これから信仰が弱くなって
When I was being interrogated,
I was afraid that I might be unfaithful
みんなをがっかりさせたらどうしよう
と思いました
to Jehovah and let my brothers down.
勾留中 一番不安だったのは
After being detained, I was mostly afraid
about what I would face in prison
刑務所で何が起きるか
—whom I would encounter, how to act,
how others would treat me—
誰にどんなことをされるのか
自分はどうすべきかが
分からなかったことです
the unknown.
When one of the officers
看守が刑務所での生活が
どれほどひどいかを話し始めました
began to describe
how bad life is behind bars,
私はダニエルを支えた天使の
挿絵を思い出し
I imagined that behind the officer
stood an angel just like the one
who supported Daniel in the illustration.
この看守の後ろにも
天使がいるんだと想像しました
This helped me to calm down
おかげで気持ちが落ち着き
恐怖心がなくなりました
and not to panic or be afraid.
That’s how Jehovah supported me.
エホバが助けてくれました
At the first court appearance,
初めて裁判に行った時
when I was brought out,
the brothers’ feelings
兄弟たちは拍手して私をサポートし
impelled them to show support somehow,
and they began applauding.
愛を表してくれました
一緒にいてくれて
本当に心強かったです
How that encouraged me
that they were with me!
Fervent and sincere prayers to Jehovah
真剣に熱烈に祈ることで
helped me to cope with these fears.
恐れを克服できました
Isaiah 30:15
イザヤ 30:15が支えになりました
gave me much support.
I realized that tranquility
平静を保ち エホバに頼ることが
一番大切だと気付きました
and trust in Jehovah
are now the most important things.
Understanding this
とても気が楽になりました
made things much easier for me.
We took the elevator down to the first floor,
エレベーターで 1階に
連れていかれました
the doors opened,
ドアが開くと
and there stood a large crowd
大勢の兄弟姉妹がそこにいて
of our brothers and sisters
拍手で出迎えてくれました
—and they all began clapping.
When I saw that, my emotions just welled up,
それを見て感動し
涙が込み上げてきました
and I got a lump in my throat.
翼が与えられたような気がしました
I felt as if I had wings;
I felt the “great cloud of witnesses.”
「大勢の証人たち」が
一緒にいるんだと思いました
エホバに 「冷静さや勇気や
知恵を与えてください
I prayed to Jehovah
for calmness, courage, and wisdom
and that he help me
not to bring reproach on his holy name.
あなたのお名前に非難をもたらすことが
ないよう助けてください」と祈りました
Almost immediately,
“the peace of God” came over me,
するとすぐに 「神からの平和」に
包まれて 穏やかな気持ちになりました
and I was calm.
The unpleasant sensations did not go away,
but I was no longer afraid.
状況は変わりませんでしたが
恐れは消えていました
While overcoming our fear,
恐れの気持ちはありましたが
my wife and I tried to go out
夫婦で毎日伝道に行くようにしました
in service every day.
自分のことではなく
他の人を助けることに思いを向けると
When you don’t concentrate on yourself
but focus on helping others, fear disappears.
恐れは消えていきます
Something that helped me
to cope with my fears
恐れを克服する助けになったのは
希望を持つことです
is hope,
looking at the situation
through Jehovah’s eyes,
エホバと同じ見方をし
先のことを考えるようにしました
seeing what will happen next
that this is not the end of the situation,
もうこれで終わりだと
考えるのではなく
but only a difficult phase
through which you can pass.
通過点にすぎないと
考えるようにしました
I was helped to cope with my fear
「今日は今日で生きよう⋯⋯真っ新な
明日が来る」という歌詞を思い出して
by the words of the song:
“Take one day at a time;
“leave tomorrow until tomorrow;
恐れを乗り越えることができました
peace is what I find.”
I understood that it was important
まだ起きていないことを
心配するのではなく
to solve problems as they came up
実際に起きた問題に
対処することが大切です
and not to be troubled
by what might never happen.
Fear is interesting;
恐れについて考えてみました
that is, in principle, fear can be
誰でも恐れを感じることはあります
inside a person, and if someone is afraid,
恐れを感じたとしても
恥じる必要はありません
that is not shameful.
でも大切なのは 恐れを克服できるか
But the question is,
Can you overcome this fear?
Can you get the fear under your control?
コントロールできるか
ネガティブな気持ちを抑えられるかと
いうことです
Can you overcome this surge of negativity?
And when my heart persuaded me to get scared,
怖いと感じたときには
エホバに祈りました
then I started to pray.
「勇気をください
I prayed to Jehovah to give me courage
何も恐れないでいられるよう
助けてください」と祈りました
and not be afraid of anyone or anything.
I still say to myself,
自分に言い聞かせます
‘Feliks, do not fear anybody
or anything except Jehovah!’
「エホバ以外の誰も
何も恐れるんじゃない！」
Dear brothers and sisters,
I really appreciate your support.
愛する兄弟姉妹
皆さんのサポートに
心から感謝しています
I’m very happy for all your letters,
皆さんの手紙や気遣いや祈り
本当にうれしいです
for all your thoughts, for all your prayers.
I really appreciate it a lot.
深く感謝しています
I try to do my best,
これからもベストを尽くします
and I try to serve Jehovah
in the best way that I can.
ベストを尽くしてエホバに仕えます
I will do that forever!
永遠にそうします